

# Enrico Liscio

PhD researcher

## Personal Details

Date of birth 20/09/1993

City Rijswijk, the Netherlands

e-mail e.liscio@tudelft.nl

Website enricoliscio.github.io

## Personal Description

I truly believe that AI is an outstanding technology that can and must be used to help society progress. So that is what I set out to do: research and develop AI that can support us in better understanding each others. And I enjoy divulging it with videos for lay-people. Furthermore, as actor and former board member of an improvisational theatre association, I learned organizational and communication skills. Curiosity keeps me alive: learning something new brightens my days.

## Working Experience

2020-present PhD researcher, TU Delft, Topic: personal values estimation in value-sensitive deliberation. Use NLP techniques to estimate individuals' personal values from text while deliberating about a topic of discussion.

2022 Visiting PhD researcher, IIIA-CSIC and University of Barcelona, International cross-topic collaboration to lay out the foundations of value inference in multiagent systems (see AAMAS '23 publication). Sponsored by TAILOR Connectivity fund.

2017–2020 Technical Lead & Deep learning developer, Fizyr, Delft RoboValley, development and implementation of state-of-the-art deep learning vision algorithms to solve challenges in automation and logistics industry.

#### Education

2015–2017 Cum laude MSc, TU Delft, Final grade: 9/10.

Systems and Control (with the Robotics Institute Excellence Scholarship)

2012–2015 Cum laude BSc, Università degli studi di Bologna, Final grade: 110L/110.

Automation Engineering

#### **Publications**

- 2023 E. Liscio, R. Lera-Leri, F. Bistaffa, R. I. J. Dobbe, C. M. Jonker, M. Lopez-Sanchez, J. A. Rodriguez-Aguilar and P. K. Murukannaiah. Value Inference in Sociotechnical Systems: Blue Sky Ideas Track. In AAMAS '23, London, UK, IFAAMAS, 1-7.
- 2022 **E. Liscio**, M. van der Meer, L. C. Siebert, C. M. Jonker, and P. K. Murukannaiah. What values should an agent align with? An Empirical Comparison of General and Context-Specific Values. *Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems*, 36(23):32.
- 2022 E. Liscio, A. E. Dondera, A Geadău, C. M. Jonker, and P. K. Murukannaiah. Cross-Domain Classification of Moral Values. In *Findings of NAACL '22*, *Seattle, USA*, ACL, 2727-2745, [Reproducibility badge (top 3%)].
- 2022 **E. Liscio**, C. M. Jonker, and P. K. Murukannaiah. Identifying Context-Specific Values via Hybrid Intelligence: Poster Track. In *HHAI '22*, Amsterdam, IOS Press, 298-301, [Best poster award].
- 2022 M. van der Meer, **E. Liscio**, C. M. Jonker, Aske Plaat, Piek Vossen, and P. K. Murukannaiah. HyEnA: A Hybrid Method for Extracting Arguments from Opinions. In *HHAI '22*, Amsterdam, IOS Press, 17-31, [Best paper award].
- 2022 L. C. Siebert, E. Liscio, P. K. Murukannaiah, L. Kaptein, S. L. Spruit, J. van den Hoven, and C. M. Jonker. Estimating Value Preferences in a Hybrid Participatory System. In HHAI '22, Amsterdam, IOS Press, 114-127, [Best paper award finalist].
- 2021 E. Liscio, M. van der Meer, L. C. Siebert, C. M. Jonker, Niek Mouter, and P. K. Murukannaiah. Axies: Identifying and Evaluating Context-Specific Values. In AAMAS '21, Online, IFAAMAS, 799-808.
- 2021 **E. Liscio**, M. van der Meer, C. M. Jonker, and P. K. Murukannaiah. A Collaborative Platform for Identifying Context-Specific Values: Demonstration Track. In *AAMAS* '21, Online, IFAAMAS, 1773-1775.

#### **Awards**

- 2022 **TAILOR Connectivity Scholarship**, Research visit scholarship, EU Horizon 2020.
- 2015–2017 **Excellence Scholarship**, *TU Delft Robotics scholarship*, Robotics institute.
- 2011–2014 Excellence Scholarship, ENASARCO scholarship, ENASARCO.

#### Invited Talks

- 2023 **Understanding Humans' Values in a Human-Al Society**, *TAILOR WP3 Work-shop*, Online.
- 2022 Estimating Context Specific Values from Natural Language, NCSU AI in Society, North Carolina, USA, [video].
- 2021 Estimating Context-Specific Values from Natural Language, *IIIA-CSIC*, Barcelona, [video].

# Conferences

- 2022 NAACL '22, Lead author and presenter, Seattle.
- 2022 HHAI '22, Poster session, Amsterdam.
- 2021 **AAMAS '21**, Lead author and presenter, Online.
- 2020 BNAIC '20, Volunteer, Online.

# Software Proficiency

| Python | •••• | SpaCy    | •••• | SQLite        | •••• |
|--------|------|----------|------|---------------|------|
| C++    | •••• | Keras/TF | •••• | ROS           | •••• |
| Linux  | •••• | PyTorch  | •••• | <b>L</b> ATEX | •••• |

### Languages

Italian Mothertongue

English IELTS Certificate - 7.5/9 Professionally fluent - C1 level

French Diplôme d'études en langue française (DELF) Can understand and speak - B1 level

#### Extra-Curricular Activities

2021-current Volleyball, Inter Rijswijk, player.

2015–2020 Improvisational theater, Delft Improv Group, improviser.

2016–2018 Board member, Delft Improv Group, chairman.

2016–2018 Volleyball/Basketball, D.S.V.V. Punch, player.

2016 Coach, TU Delft, introducing new students to the university.